# **Oreste Leone**

# Software and Game Developer

💌 <u>orleone.dev@gmail.com</u> 📞 +39 3890060229 🔗 <u>https://orleonedev.github.io</u> 📩 Naples, Italy

#### **SUMMARY**

Computer Science bachelor student and Indie Game Developer. Expertise in native iOS app and game development and frameworks, experience in Unity development for cross-platform apps. Member of Lapse Games, a small Indie Game Development Team that reached 15M+ downloads among Google Play Store and App Store with two chapters of the Lapse Trilogy.

# **RELEVANT EXPERIENCE**

### **UNITY DEVELOPER, Freelancer** — Nov 2022 - Present

- Collaborated with clients to design and develop game requirements and mechanics to include inside a Game Design Documentation;
- · Utilized Unity Engine and C# to create interactive and engaging gameplay experiences;
- · Conducted alpha and beta testing phases to gather feedback and iterate on game design;
- Communicated effectively with clients to understand their vision and provide regular updates on project progress and deadlines;

### GAME DESIGNER, Lapse Games — Oct 2017 - Present

- Conceptualised a highly successful mobile game trilogy, which has been published on both the App Store and Google Play store and has achieved over 15 million downloads worldwide with the first and second chapter;
- Collaborated with the team and external freelancers to ensure that the overall experience was engaging, entertaining and intuitive, providing localization in 32 languages;
- Designed game features and mechanics, such as in-app purchases, leaderboards and achievements that increased user engagement and retention, driving overall revenue and profitability for the game trilogy.
- Created engaging and shareable social media content, including graphics, videos, and interactive posts, that resonated with the game's target audience and helped drive user engagement.

#### **EDUCATION**

## PIER PROGRAM, Apple Developer Academy @UNINA — Jul 2022 - Jun 2023

App developer for the "mark" project, a SwiftUI based macOS tool created around Challenge Based Learning at the Apple Developer Academy.

- · Managed the developers workflow to successfully deliver continuous updates;
- Developed a web service using the Airtable platform APIs, leveraging JSON parsing, Combine, and Concurrency to retrieve and store data efficiently in the file system;
- Improved a Python based tool for user data analysis, collaborating with developers to export this data following stakeholders requirements;
- Refactored code to take advantage of the latest SwiftUI features to improve the overall project performance and structure, documenting the whole process to smoother the handover process;

## Apple Developer Academy @UNINA — Sep 2021 - Jun 2022

A Challenge Based Learning educational experience about Software Development, Entrepreneurship, App Design, and Game Creation. During this experiences I took part in the development of gamified apps and games that are available on the App Store, using native frameworks such as SwiftUI, UIKit, SpriteKit, GameplayKit and GameKit.

### Computer Science Bachelor, University of Naples Federico II — Sep 2015 - Present

Relevant Coursework and Skills: Software engineering, Human-Computer Interaction, Android Development, Data Structures and Algorithms, Multimedia Information Systems, DBMS, Web Technologies, Operating Systems, Introduction to Theoretical Computer Science, Computer Networks, Algebra and Physics.

### **SKILLS**

Swift, C, C++, C#, Objective-C, Kotlin, Java, SQL, Python, SwiftUI, UIKit, SpriteKit, GameplayKit, GameKit, Combine, Concurrency, JSON, REST API, Xcode, Core Data, Unity Engine, Unreal Engine, AR/VR, Git, Unit Testing, Design Patterns, Agile and Scrum workflow development.

#### **LANGUAGES**

Italian (Native) - English (Cambridge B2 Certificate)

I authorise the processing of personal data present in the CV pursuant to Legislative Decree .Lgs. 101/2018 and of the GDPR (EU Regulation 2016/679).